# SUJITHA PUTHANA

## CARFER OBJECTIVE

Proactive professional with 3.5+ years of experience and a proven knowledge of development, design, testing, maintenance and support of web based and client-server applications.. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the Software Developer role at your company.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### APPLICATION DEVELOPER II

Sprint Corporation, Overland Park, KS / Feb 2019 - Present

- Design effective solutions and work with the global delivery team to convert ideas into reality.
- Understand the core functionalities and perform user acceptance testing by process call records.
- SFTP call data record and communicate with different vendor on technical, functional requirements.
- Design, development, test support, deployment and production monitoring and support for service assurance platforms.
- Worked extensively with PostgreSQL Database.

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Sagarsoft Inc. Tucson, AZ / Feb 2018 - Feb 2019

- Implementation of Amadeus Revenue Integrity products from communicating/conversion of legacy Domain-specific language (APL) to modern Java code.
- Designed and developed scalable Java micro services from the ground integrating with various components like RabbitMQ, Couch base, and Web UIs to maintain products at Amadeus RI.
- Customized Restful Web Service using Restful API, sending JSON format data packets between front-end and middle-tier controller.
- Used JIRA for bug tracking and GIT for code repository and version control.
- Automated rollouts with CI/CD (Bamboo) and used Ansible for ops friendly automated deploy.
- Maven, Gradle to build application and deploy on the server.
- Proficient in unit testing frameworks like JUnit, Mockito & Jasmine.

#### SYSTEM ENGINEER

Infosys Limited, Hyderabad, Telangana / May 2014 - Jul 2016

- Designing PDF forms using Adobe LiveCycle Workbench which uses JavaScript for validating the fields at client side.
- Designing server-side validation (SSV) using XML which validates the fields at server side.
- Hands on experience in developing XML script for to configure Struts, spring, and Hibernate.
- Implemented Digital Signature for protection of information in the PDF form.
- Involved in user acceptance support and post implementation support.

□ psujitha27@gmail.com

(408) 480-0842

6929 W 141st Terrace Overland Park, KS, 66223

### **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI-KANSAS CITY

Kansas City, MO M.S. Computer Science (Dec 2017)

#### JAWAHARLAL NEHRU TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY

Hyderabad, India B.S. Information Technology (Apr 2014)

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Problem Solving Research and Development Great Team Work

# LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning specialization from Coursera Data Science specialization from Coursera